<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>alexking.org &#187; Cancer Email</title>
	<atom:link href="http://alexking.org/blog/topic/cancer-email/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://alexking.org</link>
	<description>Alex King, Denver Web Developer</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 21:04:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cycle 1 of New Trial</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/08/24/cycle-1-of-new-trial</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/08/24/cycle-1-of-new-trial#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 20:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=22038</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, I&#8217;m nearly through my first cycle of the new clinical trial and overall I think it&#8217;s gone pretty well. I was able to get the 6 pills/day (3 in the morning, 3 in the evening) without too much concern. That said, by the end of the 5 days taking the pills I would&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>I&#8217;m nearly through my first cycle of the new clinical trial and overall I think it&#8217;s gone pretty well. I was able to get the 6 pills/day (3 in the morning, 3 in the evening) without too much concern. That said,  by the end of the 5 days taking the pills I would basically sleep for the day.</p>
<p>During the 2 weeks off without pills (I&#8217;m currently on the second week of this) I&#8217;ve still had some fatigue and I&#8217;m still on the oxygen tank. However I&#8217;ve been able to get back to reading to Caitlin and doing Lego sets with her. The cough that I&#8217;d developed during by washout period before the trial has improved a bit and I think there has been a slight reduction in some of the visible tumor growth.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m still pretty limited as to what I can do physically, but I&#8217;ve enjoyed hanging out on the couch during visits from friends and family. Luckily there is plenty of golf, baseball, and now football on TV to keep me busy on the couch.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t yet know when I&#8217;ll be scheduling my next CT scan to check the effectiveness of the treatment, but I&#8217;m guessing it will be in the next 4-6 weeks.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve also started to try to compile a bit of information about me that Caitlin might find interesting later down the road. If you haven&#8217;t received an email about this effort, you probably will in the near future.</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/08/24/cycle-1-of-new-trial/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Eventful Friday Night + New Trial</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/07/30/er-visit-new-trial</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/07/30/er-visit-new-trial#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2015 19:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21984</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, On Friday afternoon I had my initial interview for the TAS-102 trial. As is standard with these appointments, we reviewed my history, the treatment schedule, side effects (they sound relatively mild), and I signed the consent form to volunteer for the study. From there I needed to get blood work and a CT&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>On Friday afternoon I had my initial interview for the TAS-102 trial. As is standard with these appointments, we reviewed my history, the treatment schedule, side effects (they sound relatively mild), and I signed the consent form to volunteer for the study. From there I needed to get blood work and a CT scan to establish my starting baseline. I was able to get these done and I started the new trial drug yesterday.</p>
<p>The schedule for this trial is a little complicated. It&#8217;s a pill rather than an infusion.</p>
<p>Week 1 &#038; 2: take 3 pills in the morning and 3 pills at night for 5 days, then 2 days off<br />
Week 3 &#038; 4: off week &#8211; no pills</p>
<p>However, there was one wrinkle. At the beginning of my appointment they took my vitals (height, weight, pulse, blood pressure, and oxygen levels). My oxygen level was too low; below 90 (which supported my anecdotal feelings of shortness of breath, etc. of late).</p>
<p>I called Kaiser and they recommended I go to Urgent Care since it was Friday at 5pm by then. We did so, but ended up at a facility that only offered Urgent Care on Saturday and Sunday. They gave me an oxygen tank and instructed us to go to the ER &#8211; basically the nurse said I was risking brain damage because of the low oxygen levels.</p>
<p>So off we went to the ER. My mom was staying with me this past week while Heather and Caitlin were visiting Heather&#8217;s family in Minnesota, so she was the lucky one that got to chauffeur and accompany me on this adventure.</p>
<p>At the ER I did my best to convince them to just give me the referral necessary for the oxygen. We were already planning to schedule the CT scan and blood work for this week, so I figured doing as little as possible at the ER was probably best. However, the ER doctor was concerned about blood clots as a potential cause of the low oxygen and wanted to run some blood work as well as a CT scan. I relented, with the caveat that we also do the CT scan I needed for the trial baseline.</p>
<p>The results were as expected: no clots or anything, the cause of the low oxygen was due to &#8220;progression of disease&#8221; &#8211; additional growth in the masses in my lungs.</p>
<p>We were able to get home just before midnight, and the folks that do the home oxygen set-up came over that night to give me a basic kit: a unit for the house with 50 feet of tubing so I can roam around like we did  back in the day before cordless telephones. They returned the next day to give us portable oxygen tanks and a unit to refill them as well.</p>
<p>So yeah, our Friday night was pretty awesome!</p>
<p>I had originally hoped to get started on this trial a few weeks ago, but as it turned out my &#8220;washout&#8221; period (time off from any treatment) ended up being a bit longer than I&#8217;d hoped while we waited for a slot to open in the trial. This has giving my fast growing cells a chance to start coming back (including the ones we don&#8217;t want). The shortness of breath has been bothering me for a week or so now and my hair started coming back in earnest around the same time.</p>
<p>Hopefully, now that I&#8217;m on the trial we&#8217;ll get some reduction in the masses in my lungs (as we have in the past) with a matching improvement in my oxygen levels.</p>
<p>Side effects-wise, the new trial shouldn&#8217;t cause hair loss like the last one did and my returning hair is coming in much darker than the hair I lost. Maybe it will lighten up again over time. The doctor told me to expect some nausea, and I did have some yesterday in my first dosage. I took an anti-nausea pill for the evening at that seemed to make things better.</p>
<p>So I&#8217;ve made it onto the trial &#8211; send good wishes for effective results and manageable side effects.</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/07/30/er-visit-new-trial/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>New trial in 2 weeks?</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/07/14/new-trial-in-2-weeks</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/07/14/new-trial-in-2-weeks#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 21:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21936</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, As expected, when I had my latest CT scan about 6 weeks ago it showed that the clinical trial I had been on since the beginning of the year was no longer being effective for me. We were expecting this based on some other symptoms, and my doctor and I had already targeted&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>As expected, when I had my latest CT scan about 6 weeks ago it showed that the clinical trial I had been on since the beginning of the year was no longer being effective for me. We were expecting this based on some other symptoms, and my doctor and I had already targeted a new trial to try to join. Since that time, I&#8217;ve been in a &#8220;washout&#8221; period &#8211; basically a period of no treatment before starting a new trial. They want to make sure that the results they are measuring are from the current trial, and that any other trial drugs have cleared your system. A 4 week period without any treatment is pretty typical.</p>
<p>I spent the month of June negotiating red tape to get an appointment to try to get into a trial for a drug called &#8220;TAS-102&#8221; based on the recommendation of my doctor at the University of Colorado (who I have been going to for the last 2 clinical trials).</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TAS-102">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TAS-102</a></p>
<p>This trial is at a different medical facility and trying to get me set up in their system was apparently non-trivial. About 2 weeks ago I was finally able to get an appointment booked to interview for the trial. Then a day later I got a call canceling the appointment because they no longer had any open slots in the trial. After taking so long to get the appointment in the first place, I found this exceedingly frustrating. Basically I was all washed out and ready for the next trial, but in need of a trial to join.</p>
<p>Thankfully, I got a call yesterday letting me know that they now had a slot available for the TAS-102 trial. I have an appointment to meet with the doctor who is administering the trial on Friday, July 24th. Hopefully things will go smoothly on both the bureaucratic and medical sides of things and I&#8217;ll be able to get going on the new trial soon thereafter.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m feeling OK, but can tell I&#8217;m no longer on treatment. I&#8217;m back to needing a shave every day or two (from once a week), and I seem to have picked up a mild cold which is causing a bit of a cough and a little shortness of breath (both familiar to me from my last washout period). I&#8217;ve had some back pain recurrence as well, but this time around it has had some direct causes and I&#8217;m better at managing it.</p>
<p>A couple of weeks ago I went camping and slept on an air mattress. That was a mistake. I had to bail and head home a day early to return to my own bed; and it took a few days to get things back under control. I had a similar situation when I flew to Seattle (and back) over the last week. Thankfully, since I&#8217;ve been through this (back pain) before, I&#8217;ve got a better sense of how to handle it this time around.</p>
<p>For example, I&#8217;ve found that using marijuana edibles when I go to bed will give me a solid night&#8217;s sleep, and it keeps me away from the unpleasant side effects of morphine pills. I also know how to stagger my pain patches and make judicious use of the hot tub and napping to help keep things under control.</p>
<p>With that in mind, I leave you with my current wish list:</p>
<p>1. an uneventful next week and a half<br />
2. that I&#8217;m able to get into the trial<br />
3. that the trial is effective</p>
<p>Thanks!</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/07/14/new-trial-in-2-weeks/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Treatment Update</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/05/25/treatment-update</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/05/25/treatment-update#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2015 18:34:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21859</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, I know it&#8217;s been a little while since I&#8217;ve sent an update, but happily that is because there hasn&#8217;t been much to report. I am still on the same clinical trial, and had a scan a month back that showed some tumor growth and some tumor shrinkage &#8211; this is what they refer&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>I know it&#8217;s been a little while since I&#8217;ve sent an update, but happily that is because there hasn&#8217;t been much to report. I am still on the same clinical trial, and had a scan a month back that showed some tumor growth and some tumor shrinkage &#8211; this is what they refer to as &#8220;stable disease&#8221;. I&#8217;m still tolerating the treatment pretty well.</p>
<p>That said, my doctor is a little concerned about some growth we&#8217;re seeing in one of my lymph nodes and we&#8217;re starting to take steps towards a different treatment so that we&#8217;re prepared in the event that my next scan shows more tumor growth than we&#8217;re comfortable with.</p>
<p>So that&#8217;s pretty much where things are.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m having good days and bad days. It&#8217;s harder for me to do physical things &#8211; probably no golf for me in the foreseeable future, and even long walks can be a challenge. However, I&#8217;ve been able to focus enough on my good days to tinker a bit on the computer and make some progress building a web app I&#8217;ve wanted to create for a while.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m also enjoying spending time with the family, and am looking forward to some trips to visit family in Seattle and Minnesota this summer. Caitlin and I are reading quite a bit together, and she&#8217;s getting better and better at reading things for herself.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll let you all know if/when things change with my treatment.</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/05/25/treatment-update/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clinical Trial Progress / CT Scan Results</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/02/13/clinical-trial-progress</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/02/13/clinical-trial-progress#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 19:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21315</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, I got some good news yesterday when I went in for treatment. The results from my CT scan earlier this week show a significant reduction in size of my abdominal lymph nodes and with the nodules in/around my liver. There is some minor growth in the nodules in my lungs, but these are&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>I got some good news yesterday when I went in for treatment. The results from my CT scan earlier this week show a significant reduction in size of my abdominal lymph nodes and with the nodules in/around my liver. There is some minor growth in the nodules in my lungs, but these are still relatively small and are &#8220;not life threatening&#8221; per my doctor. My doctor was clearly happy and excited about the results. I have been feeling better in the last few weeks after getting on a consistent trial schedule and was cautiously optimistic that the CT scan results would show that the trial drug was working.</p>
<p>It was a bit of work to get into this clinical trial, but it was definitely worth it. I&#8217;m now 5 treatments in, and the plan for now is to keep doing what we&#8217;re doing: 2 weeks on, 1 week off.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m feeling a good bit of fatigue on the treatment weeks but I felt pretty good on the off week 2 weeks ago. Hopefully I&#8217;ll be feeling good again on the off week coming up. As for the hair &#8211; it&#8217;s definitely going. I&#8217;m down to needing to shave about twice a week and the stuff on top is thinning more than it already was. Seems a reasonable trade-off to me. Now I just need to put on about 30-40 pounds again.</p>
<p>Glad to be able to share some good news after the rough patch last summer/fall. <img src="http://alexking.org/wp/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/02/13/clinical-trial-progress/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Continuing with Clinical Trial</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/01/23/continuing-with-clinical-trial</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/01/23/continuing-with-clinical-trial#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 19:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21289</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, I&#8217;m pleased to report that the liver markers in my blood work have improved as hoped after the insertion of the stent and I&#8217;ve been able to get back on the clinical trial. I had an infusion on the 15th and another yesterday (the 22nd). Based on the last two weeks it looks&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>I&#8217;m pleased to report that the liver markers in my blood work have improved as hoped after the insertion of the stent and I&#8217;ve been able to get back on the clinical trial. I had an infusion on the 15th and another yesterday (the 22nd). Based on the last two weeks it looks like I can expect about a 6-7 hour process on infusion days. Luckily the internet connection is strong and I haven&#8217;t had any trouble streaming Netflix to pass the time.</p>
<p>Side effects from this trial are fairly minimal so far and I&#8217;ve been told that I can expect them to continue as-is rather than having a growing cumulative effect. I&#8217;m experiencing some fatigue and had trouble sleeping last night, but otherwise I&#8217;m feeling pretty good (especially when I get enough sleep). The (additional) hair loss hasn&#8217;t hit me yet, but that&#8217;s expected &#8211; maybe in the next week or so.</p>
<p>My treatment schedule is 2 weeks on, 1 week off. I get a break on the 29th and then resume infusions on February 5th. I think that means I&#8217;ll be at full strength to root for my hometown Seahawks in the Super Bowl.</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/01/23/continuing-with-clinical-trial/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clinical trial delayed. :(</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/01/04/clinical-trial-delayed</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/01/04/clinical-trial-delayed#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 20:23:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, After a long battle to get into the clinical trial, I finally got my first infusion on Dec 19th. The treatment cycle is a little different than originally planned. I will have an infusion once a week for 2 weeks, then take the 3rd week off. This is preferable to the twice-a-week infusion&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>After a long battle to get into the clinical trial, I finally got my first infusion on Dec 19th. The treatment cycle is a little different than originally planned. I will have an infusion once a week for 2 weeks, then take the 3rd week off. This is preferable to the twice-a-week infusion schedule I was originally slated for.</p>
<p>The first infusion went well. I had a little nausea towards the end of the infusion and experienced a little fatigue in the week after, but overall the side effects seemed pretty manageable.</p>
<p>The schedule for infusion days follows a pretty basic pattern:</p>
<p>1. get blood drawn<br />
2. about an hour later, meet with doctor/PA/nurse to discuss how things are going and make sure there aren&#8217;t any red flags in the bloodwork results<br />
3. go for infusion</p>
<p>Step 2 has always been a formality for me &#8211; my bloodwork has come back without issues for the last two years. Unfortunately, when I went in for the 2nd infusion on December 26th there was a spike in one of the tests they do to make sure the liver is functioning well. Because of this, I couldn&#8217;t get the infusion.</p>
<p>The doctor&#8217;s hunch was that this spike was actually due to a blocked bile duct. Apparently this isn&#8217;t uncommon and the solution is to insert a stent into the bile duct to open it up. A CT would be taken to confirm the diagnosis before the procedure, then the procedure done, then over the next few days the number would return to normal (and I could get the infusion and get back on schedule with the trial).</p>
<p>That&#8217;s where things get complicated. When you&#8217;re on a clinical trial you can only stay on the trial while it is being effective for you. Normally a CT scan is done to measure effectiveness 2-3 months from the start of the trial to give the trial drug time to work. If I had a CT scan after just one treatment, it&#8217;s very likely that it would show some indication of &#8220;progression of disease&#8221; (which would force me out of the trial). So we didn&#8217;t want to do a CT scan.</p>
<p>Instead, I went in on Monday the 29th for an ultrasound. The tech who was doing the ultrasound and reading the results thought that she saw a blood clot (a portal vein thrombosis) rather than a blocked bile duct &#8211; which freaked everyone out. Again we didn&#8217;t want to do a CT scan to confirm or disprove the reading because of the clinical trial. Towards the end of the day after a lot of back and forth they decided to send me home with some blood thinners. I went to pick them up and just before I left the pharmacy with them my doctor found me.</p>
<p>He had just come from radiology where he&#8217;d asked another tech he trusted to read the ultrasound. This tech did *not* see a blood clot. We decided to skip the blood thinners for the time being and do an MRI of my liver the next day to get a better view of what was going on (but not see so much as to kick me out of the trial). I&#8217;d never had an MRI before and I&#8217;ll be happy if I never have one again. So loud and claustrophobic. I really struggled with it. Anyway, the MRI confirmed no blood clot and that the stent in the bile duct was the next step.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, this pushed us right up against New Year&#8217;s Eve. I didn&#8217;t hear from scheduling on the 31st, the 1st was a holiday and when I did hear from them on the 2nd it was too late to get the procedure done that day. I currently have an appointment on the 8th for the stent procedure, but I&#8217;m hoping to get that moved up.</p>
<p>Once the stent is installed it will take a few days for that number to come back down, and ultimately that is the gating factor to getting me back on the clinical trial; and I need to get back on the clinical trial ASAP to let the trial drug do its thing. The doctor seems really positive about the trial producing results.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a frustrating week.</p>
<p>Aside from the trial/medical-related frustration, we had a really nice holiday. I enjoyed visits from friends. My parents visited the week leading up to Christmas and Heather&#8217;s parents were in town as well. Caitlin had a blast opening her presents &#8211; everything from legos to books to stuffed animals to craft supplies to junior make-up. She&#8217;s had two weeks off from school, I think she&#8217;ll be excited to go back next week.</p>
<p>For New Year&#8217;s Eve we hosted our traditional fondue night with friends. We may have watched the ball drop in a different time zone. I wouldn&#8217;t know, I peeled off early. <img src="http://alexking.org/wp/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2015/01/04/clinical-trial-delayed/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clinical trial, hopefully starting in Dec</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/11/26/clinical-trial-hopefully-starting-in-dec</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/11/26/clinical-trial-hopefully-starting-in-dec#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 20:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21204</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, Our schedule for meeting with MD Anderson actually got moved up a bit; we met with them in Houston a week ago rather than at the beginning of this week (as originally planned). They had an interesting phase 1 trial in the &#8220;expansion stage&#8221; (it&#8217;s showing good results so they make it available&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>Our schedule for meeting with MD Anderson actually got moved up a bit; we met with them in Houston a week ago rather than at the beginning of this week (as originally planned). They had an interesting phase 1 trial in the &#8220;expansion stage&#8221; (it&#8217;s showing good results so they make it available in more locations and try it on additional types of cancer) that I was a candidate for. We also discussed the phase 2 trial available here at the University of Colorado Cancer Center.</p>
<p>Ultimately they recommended, and we have decided to go ahead with, the phase 2 trial here in Colorado. The details are here for anyone curious about the study drug:</p>
<p><a href="http://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01915472">http://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01915472</a></p>
<p>Basically I will have antibodies that want to go after my cancer cells injected into me. The CU folks have had patients on this drug for a little while now (some as long as 10 months) and have seen some good success with it. I hope I will be one of their success stories.</p>
<p>The main side effects seem to be fatigue and a loss of all (or the rest of..) my hair. Oh well.</p>
<p>I have started the process of qualifying for the trial and if all goes well I will be starting on Dec 15th. That&#8217;s about as soon as I&#8217;m eligible after a 28 day &#8220;washout&#8221; period (not taking any other cancer drugs). The schedule goes like this: for 2 weeks I will be getting an infusion twice a week (on Monday and Thursday); then I take the 3rd week off. Lather, rinse, repeat.</p>
<p>So now I just need to get through the next couple of weeks sans-treatment, and need things to go well so that I&#8217;m accepted into the trial. Thanks in advance for all Good Thoughts, etc. you can send our way.</p>
<p>I hope you all have a great Thanksgiving!</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/11/26/clinical-trial-hopefully-starting-in-dec/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Next Steps for Me</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/11/16/next-steps-for-me</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/11/16/next-steps-for-me#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 23:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21198</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, I&#8217;m doing pretty well. My weight and strength are still down from where I&#8217;d like them, but I&#8217;m enjoying being home with Caitlin. I&#8217;m getting in a good nap or two a day as needed with the &#8220;may cause drowsiness&#8221; label on just about everything I take these days. Sometimes I doze off&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>I&#8217;m doing pretty well. My weight and strength are still down from where I&#8217;d like them, but I&#8217;m enjoying being home with Caitlin. I&#8217;m getting in a good nap or two a day as needed with the &#8220;may cause drowsiness&#8221; label on just about everything I take these days. Sometimes I doze off sitting on the couch while watching a football game; I&#8217;ve got all sorts of new skills. I&#8217;ve started reading the next books in the Game of Thrones series &#8211; these are long books; I&#8217;ve got some runway. We had our first snow of the season last week and it&#8217;s been absurdly cold the last week and things don&#8217;t look much better for next week. I&#8217;m looking forward to a thaw in our near future.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a little while since I&#8217;ve written, and a number of things have been in motion.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d been exploring a number of clinical trials that had been identified as possibilities, but nearly all of these ended up not being options. I&#8217;m hoping that there may be some options through the NCI (National Cancer Institute) that I can still explore.</p>
<p>I had a CT scan at the end of October which showed that my tumors are still finding my lungs to be fertile ground &#8211; they have grown and are more numerous than before. There also may be some tumor activity in/around my liver that is concerning. Because of this, we&#8217;re considering the Regorafenib treatment to be unsuccessful. However the Regorafenib has been very helpful in managing my pain, so I&#8217;ve stayed on it for the last two weeks for that reason.</p>
<p>The cancer center at the University of Colorado has identified 2 new clinical trials I can participate in, and I&#8217;m likely to sign up for one of these. I&#8217;m working to get a better idea of which one the doctors think will be more effective.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve also got an appointment a week from Monday at the MD Anderson clinic in Houston to talk to their clinical trial folks and see if anything they have to offer might be a good option for me.</p>
<p>Since it looks like I&#8217;ll be getting on a clinical trial sooner rather than later, I&#8217;ve gone off of Regorafenib as of this weekend. Most all of these trials require a 28 day &#8220;washout&#8221; period where I&#8217;m not on any other treatments before going on their treatment. The last time I took a break from Regorafenib, I started experiencing a lot of back pain. I&#8217;m hoping that we&#8217;re able to manage the pain OK without it, but I&#8217;m definitely a little concerned.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m going to be experimenting with my diet a bit as well. It&#8217;s been a challenge when one of my problems has been keeping weight on, but going to more of a raw foods/veggie diet probably won&#8217;t hurt anything and might help a bit. We&#8217;ll see how I do with it.</p>
<p>Hopefully the next trial I get myself on will be successful in reducing the size of these tumors in my lungs/liver. Otherwise my prognosis just isn&#8217;t very good.</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/11/16/next-steps-for-me/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back pain returned and now receding</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/10/27/back-pain-returned-and-now-receding</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/10/27/back-pain-returned-and-now-receding#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 16:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21125</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[3 weeks ago things were going so well with my back pain that I was backing off my meds and thinking about how best to up my physical activity. Last week I got hit by the proverbial truck. Thankfully, I&#8217;m already making progress managing coming out the other side. My current cancer treatment (Regorafenib) has&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>3 weeks ago things were going so well with my back pain that I was backing off my meds and thinking about how best to up my physical activity. Last week I got hit by the proverbial truck. Thankfully, I&#8217;m already making progress managing coming out the other side.</p>
<p>My current cancer treatment (Regorafenib) has a 3 week on, 1 week off dosing schedule. I had actually run a little long so took my off week after 4 weeks on. That off week corresponded with nearly a full return of my back pain. Primarily muscular pain. I got some relief from acupuncture but also heavily ramped up my pain meds and was frequently using the morphine for &#8220;breakthrough&#8221; pain on top of the pain patches.</p>
<p>I started up my Regorafenib treatment again on Friday last week and already managed to have a real night&#8217;s sleep on Saturday night (last night was a little rougher, but was still a huge improvement over the previous week). We aren&#8217;t sure how the Regorafenib is helping here, but I&#8217;ll take it. I&#8217;m having a scan today. It&#8217;s a little early to really see what the Regorafenib may be doing in terms of it&#8217;s effectiveness, but my doctor wanted to take a peek and see how things are coming along.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m hoping to hear back from the National Cancer Institute on a few possible clinical trials this week, and have made good progress through the rest of the list. As expected, many of the trials were not a good fit (only enrolling breast cancer patients now, only open to patients with genetic marker X, etc.) but many of them offered other possible trials. I hope we&#8217;ll be working with the doctors to evaluate options here in the near term to see what our next steps should be, given the options from the trial research.</p>
<p>So that&#8217;s the update &#8211; a pretty rough week, but doing better again now. Hopefully things will continue to improve as before, and we&#8217;ll be a little more cautious about the next &#8220;off week&#8221; from treatment.</p>
<p>Oh &#8211; and I hope you&#8217;re all watching the World Series; it&#8217;s been great so far!</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/10/27/back-pain-returned-and-now-receding/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Not much to report</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/10/13/not-much-to-report</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/10/13/not-much-to-report#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 19:16:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21123</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, There isn&#8217;t *too* much to report since my last email, but it&#8217;s generally good news. I&#8217;ve made consistent progress in rebounding from the debilitating back pain I was experiencing. I&#8217;m still down about 15 pounds (and struggling to put that back on), but my back pain is largely gone. I&#8217;ve got to credit&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>There isn&#8217;t *too* much to report since my last email, but it&#8217;s generally good news. I&#8217;ve made consistent progress in rebounding from the debilitating back pain I was experiencing. I&#8217;m still down about 15 pounds (and struggling to put that back on), but my back pain is largely gone. I&#8217;ve got to credit my acupuncture treatments for a lot of my progress, and I&#8217;ve been on various pain medications while we worked to get that under control.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve just reduced my pain patch dosage down to 25 micrograms (it was 100 micrograms initially), so that&#8217;s great news. I&#8217;m sleeping reasonably and not experiencing too much tumor-related pain. The pain meds I have been on have made me feel cold (I&#8217;m pretty much perpetually in a heavy sweatshirt or down shirt), so I&#8217;m glad to be ramping down on those. My back still gets tired, I think I need to look at starting some physical therapy to build strength.</p>
<p>The Regorafenib treatment is no fun as expected. I&#8217;m still working on ramping up the dosage but I&#8217;m very fatigued and napping frequently; and the soles of my feel are sore and painful. However I&#8217;m still able to walk a bit and have been walking Caitlin to school in the mornings. I&#8217;m a bit slow on the return trip &#8211; walking downhill is harder! We will check progress with another scan in a month or so.</p>
<p>I stepped away from work on September 15th and am now on medical leave. I hope that I&#8217;ll be in position to return after participating in a trial successfully, but I&#8217;m not too worried about getting back just yet.</p>
<p>With some help from my mom, I&#8217;ve started contacting a list of ~30 or so clinical trials that might be an option for me. The expectation is that about 25-33% will be possibilities, then we&#8217;ll evaluate which we think is the best option. There are some pretty cool things happening in these trials, so hopefully I&#8217;ll find something that can do good work for me.</p>
<p>Heather was out of town this past weekend on a girls trip am I&#8217;m pleased to say that the dog, Caitlin, and I all survived (I had some help). The trip to Maine last week with Heather and Caitlin was wonderful. Great times with great friends, and some very special moments. I&#8217;m looking forward to my conference in San Francisco at the end of the month as well.</p>
<p>So that&#8217;s where I am right now &#8211; in a bit of a holding pattern and doing my best to smell the flowers along the way.</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/10/13/not-much-to-report/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>We&#8217;re gonna need a new clinical trial</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/09/10/were-gonna-need-a-new-clinical-trial</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/09/10/were-gonna-need-a-new-clinical-trial#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 03:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, We got some bad news about a week ago. I had a CT scan and discovered that the clinical trial I was on was not yielding the results were were hoping for. The scan showed some new growth during the time I was I was on the trial drug and my doctor determined&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>We got some bad news about a week ago. I had a CT scan and discovered that the clinical trial I was on was not yielding the results were were hoping for. The scan showed some new growth during the time I was I was on the trial drug and my doctor determined it was best to stop treatment.</p>
<p>The new plan is to start on Regorafenib (I can now spell this correctly without looking it up!), a drug that should help stabilize things while we look for a trial that can hopefully walk back some of the new cancer growth we&#8217;ve seen in the past few months. Rogorafenib has some unpleasant side effects so I&#8217;m hopeful a new, promising trial can be found soon.</p>
<p>That back pain I mentioned previously? Yeah, it&#8217;s probably related to the new cancer growth. We&#8217;re still working on figuring out exactly the right dosage and delivery of my pain medication, but feel like we&#8217;ve made progress on that front in the last few days. Once I get the pain in check (and the associated constipation from the pain meds under control, etc.), I should be able to make progress on regaining some of the recent weight and strength I&#8217;ve lost.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve also decided that this is a good time to take a medical leave of absence from work. I&#8217;ll be stepping away and transferring my responsibilities to other folks on the team &#8211; we announced this to them today.</p>
<p>I have two work-ish conference trips planned in October and at this time I still plan to attend both of them (Monktoberfest and WordCamp SF). I look forward to seeing some of you there. Beyond that, we&#8217;ll be here in Denver. If you are coming through town please drop a note so that we can connect.</p>
<p>Hopefully we&#8217;ll find a trial that works well for me and allows me to get back to work and the other things I enjoy in the near future. In the meantime I will be doing my best to take care of myself and enjoy time with family and friends (who have been amazingly supportive &#8211; thank you to all of you).</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/09/10/were-gonna-need-a-new-clinical-trial/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clinical trial update</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/08/25/clinical-trial-update</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/08/25/clinical-trial-update#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 20:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21119</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, It&#8217;s starting to feel like the end of summer here and the beginning of the beautiful fall season here in Colorado. Caitlin has a week of kindergarten under her belt and seems to be doing great. Heather and I walk her the few blocks up to school every day, which is really nice.&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>It&#8217;s starting to feel like the end of summer here and the beginning of the beautiful fall season here in Colorado. Caitlin has a week of kindergarten under her belt and seems to be doing great. Heather and I walk her the few blocks up to school every day, which is really nice. Caitlin and I went to a Rockies game with another dad and daughter yesterday &#8211; we made it through all 9 innings, though the last 2.5 were spent eating an ice cream helmet sundae. We are heading up to Lake McConaughy http://ilovelakemac.com/ for labor day weekend with Heather&#8217;s parents and another family. Expectations are already set &#8211; we&#8217;ll be sleeping on the beach in a trailer with sand in everything. It should be a fun trip.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m 3 weeks in on my clinical trial (here are the details: http://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01988896 ). It&#8217;s an infusion every 2 weeks and pills twice a week. After the first infusion I had a wicked headache for a day or so, but I didn&#8217;t experience that after the second infusion. I&#8217;m told another local participant had the same experience and hasn&#8217;t had the headache since, so hopefully I have the same experience. The primary side effect I&#8217;ve experienced is fatigue &#8211; I&#8217;m sleeping more and needing to go to bed earlier. The facial rash and diarrhea have been pretty well managed with additional medication.</p>
<p>Overall I think I&#8217;m tolerating the trial drugs pretty well. My blood work looks very solid and I haven&#8217;t had to reduce dosage like some trial participants have. I was able to participate in a golf tournament with a client on Tuesday afternoon last week, just one day after my Monday infusion (though I then needed to rest a bit on Wednesday).</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been experiencing some intermittent back pain for the last month or so, and it got pretty bad this weekend. When I went in for my blood draw and clinic visit today they prescribed Oxycodone for me. I took one this afternoon and am feeling much better. I&#8217;m hoping that I&#8217;ll be using these somewhat occasionally rather than turning into Gregory House (http://house.wikia.com/wiki/Gregory_House). We&#8217;ll be doing a scan in the near future to get a better sense of what is causing the back pain, but it&#8217;s too early to gauge if the trial drugs are being effective or not. We&#8217;ll hope to start getting a sense of effectiveness about 8 weeks in.</p>
<p>I hope you all have a great labor day weekend!</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/08/25/clinical-trial-update/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clinical trial, day one</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/08/04/clinical-trial-day-one</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/08/04/clinical-trial-day-one#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 17:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21117</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, I&#8217;m getting started on my clinical trial today. It&#8217;s a combination of an infusion (every 2 weeks, like before) and a pill that I take twice a week. The trial drugs are attempting to block the cancer cells from continuing to grow by signal blocking at two different levels. They refer to this&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>I&#8217;m getting started on my clinical trial today. It&#8217;s a combination of an infusion (every 2 weeks, like before) and a pill that I take twice a week. The trial drugs are attempting to block the cancer cells from continuing to grow by signal blocking at two different levels. They refer to this as &#8220;targeted therapy&#8221; rather than &#8220;chemotherapy&#8221; &#8211; chemo is like using a shotgun (blast everything) vs the targeted therapy which is more like using a (relatively aimed) handgun. In the future there is hope of more of a sniper rifle approach (already being tried for other kinds of cancer).</p>
<p>Expected side effects are digestion related (nausea, diarrhea) as both drugs hit that system. I&#8217;m told to expect an acne-like rash on my face too &#8211; good times! However they seem pretty positive about the drug&#8217;s effectiveness, so those are fine trade-offs in my book.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m at the University of Colorado Cancer Center for the trial instead of the Kaiser hospital I&#8217;ve been visiting for the last 18 months. The CU Cancer Center on the opposite side of town and traffic is a bit of a mess, but it&#8217;s a very nice facility and it has fantastic WiFi! The doctors, nurses and other folks I&#8217;ve interacted with so far have all been both friendly and competent &#8211; always a good combination.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be visiting the hospital with some regularity since this is a trial and they need to measure the results and side effects. This week I&#8217;m back tomorrow morning and Thursday; then again twice the following week and three times the next week (once for infusion, etc.). After that things begin to taper off a bit.</p>
<p>I had the port installed in my chest so that I wouldn&#8217;t need to get IVs for infusions, blood draws, etc. However for these initial infusions I have to get an IV in my arm in addition to the port because they are using my port for blood draws (getting measurements) and don&#8217;t want the trial drugs to taint the results. The IV hurts. <img src="http://alexking.org/wp/wp-includes/images/smilies/frownie.png" alt=":(" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> They brought down their &#8220;vein whisperer&#8221; nurse to stick me because I told them about my previous troubles getting an IV during my surgical hospital stay.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m pretty optimistic that I&#8217;ll be able keep the same work schedule (or better) that I had during my previous chemo treatments.</p>
<p>The Benadryl they gave me before they started the infusion is making it hard for me to focus my eyes, not to mention keep them open so I&#8217;ll sign off for now. Fingers crossed for lots of desired effects and few side effects.</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/08/04/clinical-trial-day-one/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hey, an update!</title>
		<link>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/07/02/hey-an-update</link>
		<comments>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/07/02/hey-an-update#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 16:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alex]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer Email]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexking.org/?p=21115</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hi Everyone, I&#8217;ve been doing well. I&#8217;m currently halfway through a week in Minnesota with Caitlin, Heather, Heather&#8217;s parents, and her brother&#8217;s family (our annual MN trip). I&#8217;ve done a little work travel as well, and have been getting out to the golf course regularly. We are planning to visit Seattle later in the month,&#8230;]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been doing well. I&#8217;m currently halfway through a week in Minnesota with Caitlin, Heather, Heather&#8217;s parents, and her brother&#8217;s family (our annual MN trip). I&#8217;ve done a little work travel as well, and have been getting out to the golf course regularly. We are planning to visit Seattle later in the month, and are looking forward to seeing friends and family there.</p>
<p>Work continues to go well; bringing new and interesting challenges that come with scaling a larger organization. I&#8217;m also still getting to work directly on the tech, which I really enjoy.</p>
<p>Caitlin just got a cast off her arm. She had fallen on the playground on Memorial Day weekend and broken the bones in her right arm near her wrist. They have healed well and she&#8217;s enjoying her re-found freedom. Casts are pretty cool these days. It was fiberglass and she could even go swimming with it.</p>
<p>On to the health update. After a total of 25 chemo treatments, the doctors determined that the chemo (FOLFOX, then FOLFIRI) was no longer being effective. A scan a few weeks back showed incremental growth in the lung tumors &#8211; up to about .5cm of growth in the previous 3 months and an enlarged lymph node in my lower back. The cancer cells learn and adapt to the chemo over time, so this was expected.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m now working with doctors at the University of Colorado cancer center to get access to clinical trials. I&#8217;ve got a spot in a trial that is a late phase 1 trial that uses two different drugs to try to block cancer cell growth at 2 different levels (the currently approved treatment only blocks at one level, and is typically only effective for a short period of time &#8211; the hope is that blocking at 2 levels will make it more effective, longer). My spot opens at the end of the month (and there is a 3-4 week &#8220;drying out&#8221; period required for clinical trials), so I&#8217;ll be enjoying a month off from chemo in the meantime.</p>
<p>A phase 2 trial means that the drugs have already been used on humans once, a phase 1 trial has only been tested on animals. In this case, the initial phase 1 trial showed that the initial dosage of one of the drugs was too much for people to handle, so it is being scaled back for the late phase 1 trial. The side effects look similar to the side effects of my most recent chemo treatments, plus some skin irritation (acne/rash) &#8211; at least on paper.</p>
<p>I also learned that immunotherapy, which looks very promising for other kinds of cancer, is not showing to be effective (so far) in colon cancer. The guess is that it has to do with the gut being home to so many different bacteria, etc. That&#8217;s a bummer.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll let you all know how the new drugs are treating me in about a month or so; and any updates in the interim.</p>
<p class="threads-post-notice">This post is part of the thread: <a href="http://alexking.org/blog/thread/cancer">Cancer</a> &#8211; an ongoing story on this site. View the thread timeline for more context on this post.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexking.org/blog/2014/07/02/hey-an-update/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.392 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2015-09-28 14:02:51 -->

<!-- Compression = gzip -->